{
  "name": "Pop Culture",
  "language": "en",
  "theme": "pop_culture",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "pc_0001",
      "question": "Who created Mickey Mouse?",
      "correct_answer": "Walt Disney"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0002",
      "question": "What is the highest-grossing movie of all time?",
      "correct_answer": "Avatar (2009)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0003",
      "question": "Which artist painted 'The Starry Night'?",
      "correct_answer": "Vincent van Gogh"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0004",
      "question": "What was the first video game console?",
      "correct_answer": "Magnavox Odyssey"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0005",
      "question": "Who wrote the Harry Potter series?",
      "correct_answer": "J.K. Rowling"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0006",
      "question": "What is the most-viewed video on YouTube of all time?",
      "correct_answer": "Baby Shark Dance"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0007",
      "question": "Which film won the first Academy Award for Best Picture?",
      "correct_answer": "Wings (1927)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0008",
      "question": "What is the best-selling album of all time?",
      "correct_answer": "Thriller by Michael Jackson"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0009",
      "question": "Who invented the World Wide Web?",
      "correct_answer": "Tim Berners-Lee"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0010",
      "question": "What was the first film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
      "correct_answer": "Iron Man (2008)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0051",
      "question": "Which country hosts a World Air Guitar Championship?",
      "correct_answer": "Finland"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0052",
      "question": "Which product is banned for sale in Singapore?",
      "correct_answer": "Chewing gum"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0053",
      "question": "Which Disney character lost a shoe on the stairs?",
      "correct_answer": "Cinderella"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0054",
      "question": "What object is chased down a hill at Cooper’s Hill Festival in England?",
      "correct_answer": "A cheese"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0055",
      "question": "What is Japan’s national sport?",
      "correct_answer": "Sumo"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0056",
      "question": "What fruit did Carmen Miranda famously wear on her head?",
      "correct_answer": "Bananas"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0057",
      "question": "Which popular brand first dressed Santa Claus in red?",
      "correct_answer": "Coca-Cola"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0058",
      "question": "Which animal was once tried and executed in France in the 15th century?",
      "correct_answer": "A pig"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0059",
      "question": "What instrument does Lisa Simpson play?",
      "correct_answer": "Saxophone"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0060",
      "question": "In which city is the Museum of Ice Cream located?",
      "correct_answer": "New York City"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0061",
      "question": "Which company created the character Sonic?",
      "correct_answer": "SEGA"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0062",
      "question": "In which country was karaoke invented?",
      "correct_answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0063",
      "question": "Which artist wore a dress made of meat at an awards show?",
      "correct_answer": "Lady Gaga"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0064",
      "question": "Which popular movie features a green ogre as the main character?",
      "correct_answer": "Shrek"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0065",
      "question": "What is the name of Mickey Mouse’s dog?",
      "correct_answer": "Pluto"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0066",
      "question": "Which popular social network was inspired by instant photography?",
      "correct_answer": "Instagram"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0067",
      "question": "Which character lives in a pineapple under the sea?",
      "correct_answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0068",
      "question": "Which video game features a storm that shrinks the playing area?",
      "correct_answer": "Fortnite"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0069",
      "question": "What is the official mascot of Android?",
      "correct_answer": "A green robot called Bugdroid"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0070",
      "question": "Which singer launched a perfume called 'Heat'?",
      "correct_answer": "Beyoncé"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0071",
      "question": "What is the theme of the annual festival held in Avon, Ohio?",
      "correct_answer": "Duct tape"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0072",
      "question": "Which country hosts an annual nap competition?",
      "correct_answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0073",
      "question": "What animal appeared in Twitter’s logo?",
      "correct_answer": "A bird"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0074",
      "question": "What invention was created by accident while trying to make a stronger glue?",
      "correct_answer": "Post-it"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0075",
      "question": "Which actor said the famous line 'Sayonara, baby'?",
      "correct_answer": "Arnold Schwarzenegger"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0076",
      "question": "What food fell from the sky in the 2009 animated movie?",
      "correct_answer": "Food"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0077",
      "question": "What color are Papa Smurf’s pants?",
      "correct_answer": "Red"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0078",
      "question": "Which singer went on stage wearing a giant lobster on her head?",
      "correct_answer": "Lady Gaga"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0079",
      "question": "Which city has a cathedral made of human bones?",
      "correct_answer": "Kutná Hora (Czech Republic)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0080",
      "question": "Which company launched the first phone with a built-in camera?",
      "correct_answer": "Sharp"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0081",
      "question": "Which country invented the sandwich?",
      "correct_answer": "United Kingdom"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0082",
      "question": "Which fruit is banned in some Asian hotels because of its smell?",
      "correct_answer": "Durian"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0083",
      "question": "What object do world Monopoly champions use to decide the order of play?",
      "correct_answer": "A golden die"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0084",
      "question": "Which country has a green sand beach?",
      "correct_answer": "Hawaii (United States)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0085",
      "question": "Which movie made the shark named Bruce famous?",
      "correct_answer": "Finding Nemo"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0086",
      "question": "Which country holds a mobile phone throwing competition?",
      "correct_answer": "Finland"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0087",
      "question": "Which vegetable has been used as a musical instrument in Vienna?",
      "correct_answer": "Carrots"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0088",
      "question": "Which singer jokingly claimed to have kissed an alien?",
      "correct_answer": "Katy Perry"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0089",
      "question": "Which U.S. city has a museum dedicated exclusively to toilets?",
      "correct_answer": "San Antonio, Texas"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0090",
      "question": "Which drink was originally created as a headache medicine?",
      "correct_answer": "Coca-Cola"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0091",
      "question": "Which country has a law that forbids owning just one guinea pig because they get lonely?",
      "correct_answer": "Switzerland"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0092",
      "question": "Which food was used by the U.S. Army to develop adhesives during World War II?",
      "correct_answer": "Peanuts"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0093",
      "question": "Which city hosts a marathon where participants run dressed as Santa Claus?",
      "correct_answer": "Liverpool"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0094",
      "question": "Which animal can sleep for up to three years?",
      "correct_answer": "The snail"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0095",
      "question": "Which country has vending machines that sell live crabs?",
      "correct_answer": "China"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0096",
      "question": "Which invention was created by accident while trying to make stronger paint?",
      "correct_answer": "The microwave"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0097",
      "question": "Which singer was supposedly hired by the Norwegian government to scare fish?",
      "correct_answer": "Björk (urban legend)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0098",
      "question": "Which country holds an annual massive pillow fight?",
      "correct_answer": "The Netherlands"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0099",
      "question": "What Greek word literally means 'fear of working'?",
      "correct_answer": "Ergophobia"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0100",
      "question": "Which company sold a 'block of air' supposedly from Kanye West for $60?",
      "correct_answer": "eBay"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0101",
      "question": "Which country has an island inhabited almost entirely by rabbits?",
      "correct_answer": "Japan (Ōkunoshima)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0102",
      "question": "Which actor owns a lake in Canada named 'Keanu Lake'?",
      "correct_answer": "Keanu Reeves"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0103",
      "question": "Which country has a museum dedicated to the oldest bread in the world?",
      "correct_answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0104",
      "question": "Which city hosts a parade where thousands of people dress as zombies?",
      "correct_answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0105",
      "question": "Which animal is legally considered property of the British monarch if found in the Thames?",
      "correct_answer": "The swan"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0106",
      "question": "What object was accidentally launched into space and cataloged as 'space debris number 43137'?",
      "correct_answer": "A spatula"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0107",
      "question": "Which country has a festival where people throw giant tomatoes at each other?",
      "correct_answer": "Spain (La Tomatina)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0108",
      "question": "Which modern invention was inspired by a 1940s comic strip called Dick Tracy?",
      "correct_answer": "The smartwatch"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0109",
      "question": "Which artist taped a banana to a wall and sold it for $120,000?",
      "correct_answer": "Maurizio Cattelan"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0110",
      "question": "Which country hosts an official wife-carrying competition?",
      "correct_answer": "Finland"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0111",
      "question": "Which invention was inspired by burrs that stuck to a dog's fur during a walk?",
      "correct_answer": "Velcro"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0112",
      "question": "What is the name of the Japanese island famous for being inhabited mostly by cats?",
      "correct_answer": "Aoshima"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0113",
      "question": "Which ice sport uses brooms and sliding stones to reach a target circle?",
      "correct_answer": "Curling"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0114",
      "question": "In which country is there a contest to freeze hairstyles in outdoor hot springs?",
      "correct_answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0115",
      "question": "What food has a museum in Ikeda (Osaka) where you can design your own cup?",
      "correct_answer": "Instant ramen (Cup Noodles)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0116",
      "question": "What is the fear of extremely long words called?",
      "correct_answer": "Hippopotomonstrosesquipedaliophobia"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0117",
      "question": "In which country were turnips carved for Halloween before pumpkins became popular?",
      "correct_answer": "Ireland"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0118",
      "question": "What is the real-world sport inspired by Quidditch from Harry Potter now called?",
      "correct_answer": "Quadball (formerly Quidditch)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0119",
      "question": "Which Japanese fruit can sell for thousands of dollars per pair due to its perfection?",
      "correct_answer": "Yubari melon"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0120",
      "question": "What is the world’s shortest commercial flight, lasting just over one minute?",
      "correct_answer": "Westray–Papa Westray (Scotland)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0121",
      "question": "What object drops every New Year’s Eve in Times Square, New York City?",
      "correct_answer": "A crystal ball"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0122",
      "question": "What colour M&M was discontinued in 1976 due to dye concerns and later brought back?",
      "correct_answer": "Red"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0123",
      "question": "Which living creatures were sent into space in 1947 before humans?",
      "correct_answer": "Fruit flies"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0124",
      "question": "Which bird is capable of flying backwards?",
      "correct_answer": "The hummingbird"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0125",
      "question": "What is the U.S. competition called where people catapult pumpkins?",
      "correct_answer": "Punkin Chunkin"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0126",
      "question": "What Spanish tradition involves a man jumping over babies to 'ward off evil'?",
      "correct_answer": "El Colacho (Castrillo de Murcia)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0127",
      "question": "In which city is the Museum of Broken Relationships located?",
      "correct_answer": "Zagreb (Croatia)"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0128",
      "question": "Which movie made the volleyball named Wilson famous?",
      "correct_answer": "Cast Away"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0129",
      "question": "What title did an executive almost give to 'Back to the Future'?",
      "correct_answer": "Spaceman from Pluto"
    },
    {
      "id": "pc_0130",
      "question": "Which large animal is physically unable to jump?",
      "correct_answer": "The elephant"
    }
  ]
}
